Six villagers. Two teams. One goal:
the first crafted iron pickaxe wins.
No scripts. Each villager thinks with a local LLM
every 10 seconds — llama3.1:8b, running on one PC.
Normal difficulty. Hostile mobs on.
Zero human intervention from the starting gun.
The wood age: axes are free, ores are gated.
Every tool is a project, not a wish.
RED draws first blood — first coal,
3 minutes 47 into the race.
BLUE answers 27 seconds later.
Both teams have fuel. The ladder steepens.
BLUE mines first iron — stone pickaxes only;
the tool gate taught them the hard way.
RED finds iron a minute later.
Four rungs down, two to go — anyone's race.
BLUE crafts a furnace. 9 minutes flat.
The win is one smelt away.
FEN OF BLUE: three ingots smelted and the
IRON PICKAXE CRAFTED — one action, race over.
11 minutes, 0.6 seconds. Judged from an
append-only event ledger — not a screenshot.
Honest-race assertion: CLEAN. Zero scripted
decisions, zero budget trips, zero deaths.
Every milestone replayable by one curl.